// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let Maths = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Ordinary table salt is sodium chloride. What is baking soda?",
    answer: "D.	Sodium bicarbonate",
    options: [
      "A.	Potassium chloride",
      "B.	Potassium carbonate",
      "C.	Potassium hydroxide",
      "D.	Sodium bicarbonate"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Ozone hole refers to",
    answer:  "(c) 25",
    options: [
      "A.	hole in ozone layer",
      "B.	decrease in the ozone layer in troposphere",
      "C.	decrease in thickness of ozone layer in stratosphere",
      "D.	increase in the thickness of ozone layer in troposphere"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Pollination is best defined as",
    answer:  "A.	transfer of pollen from anther to stigma",
    options: [
      "A.	transfer of pollen from anther to stigma",
      "B.	germination of pollen grains",
      "C.	growth of pollen tube in ovule",
      "D.	visiting flowers by insects"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Pine, fir, spruce, cedar, larch and cypress are the famous timber-yielding plants of which several also occur widely in the hilly regions of India. All these belong to",
    answer:"(b) irrational",
    options: [
      "A.	angiosperms",
      "B.	gymnosperms",
      "C.	monocotyledons",
      "D.	dicotyledons"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Photosynthesis generally takes place in which parts of the plant?",
    answer:   "A. eXtensible Markup Language", 
    options: [
      "A.	Leaf and other chloroplast bearing parts",
      "B.	stem and leaf",
      "C.	Roots and chloroplast bearing parts",
      "D.	Bark and leaf"
    ]
  },
  {
      numb: 6,
      question:"Plants receive their nutrients mainly from",
      answer: "D.	soil",
      options:[
        "A.	chlorophyll",
        "B.	atmosphere",
        "C.	light",
        "D.	soil"
      ]
  },
 {
     numb: 7,
     question: "Movement of cell against concentration gradient is called",
     answer: "A.	osmosis",
      options:[
        "A.	osmosis",
        "B.	active transport",
        "C.	diffusion",
        "D.	passive transport"
      ]
 },
 {
     numb: 8,
     question: "Plants synthesis protein from",
     answer:  "C.	amino acids",
     options:[
         "A.	starch",
         "B.	sugar",
         "C.	amino acids",
         "D.	fatty acids"

     ]
 },
 {
    numb: 9,
     question: "Plants absorb dissolved nitrates from soil and convert them into",
     answer:  "A.	free nitrogen",
     options:[
         "A.	free nitrogen",
         "B.	urea",
         "C.	ammonia",
         "D.	proteins"

     ]
 },
 {
    numb: 10,
     question: "One of the following is not a function of bones.",
     answer:  "C.	Secretion of hormones for calcium regulation in blood and bones",
     options:[
         "A.	Place for muscle attachment",
         "B.	Protection of vital organs",
         "C.	Secretion of hormones for calcium regulation in blood and bones",
         "D.	Production of blood corpuscles"

     ]
 }
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];